TheChaosLegion
l want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
l will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
lf only our hearts could connect,
l could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and l know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
l'll be there for you.
l hope l can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
～♪
（バルサ）二つ月？
A double moon?
チャグム 走れ！
Chagum! Run!
Episode 3
Fight
to
the
Death
チャグム 荷を捨てて森へ走るんだ
Chagum, drop what you're carrying
and run for the forest.
早く！
（チャグム）あっ…
Hurry!
Why aren't you using
your blowguns to kill the prince?
なぜ 吹き矢で皇子を狙わない？
You've switched to a
different formation, l see.
（バルサ）
フォーメーションを変えたね
皇子を亡き者にするのは
やめたのかい？
Have you given up on
trying to kill the prince?
森の奥に逃げるんだよ！
Run into the forest!
（ジン）待て
Wait.
l'll go after the woman.
女は 俺が追う
ゼンは チャグム皇子を
ユンは お頭を頼む
Zen, you take Prince Chagum.
Yun, you look after the commander.
Balsa?
バルサ？
は… 放せ！ 嫌だ！
Unhand me! Let go!
We got careless.
（ゼン）ぬかったな
（ゼン）
４人がかりで しとめられないとは
l can't believe that the four of us
working together couldn't kill her.
What of the woman?
女は？
She is most formidable.
Not a step since she entered the forest.
（ジン）恐ろしいヤツだ
森に入ってからは 一歩も動かない
l'm sure she was slit in the stomach
by the commander's sword.
お頭の太刀で腹を斬られたはずだ
すぐにでも
逃げたくなりそうなものだが
Such a wound would compel
most people to flee, but not her.
お頭を襲った一撃も
相打ち覚悟で突っ込んでいた
And she attacked him fully prepared
to receive a death blow herself.
斬られると分かっていて
なお踏み込むことができるのは―
That she could still charge him
knowing she'd be slashed...
相当な修羅場をくぐってきた証し
...shows that she has
survived many battles.
True.
But at the end of the day,
she's just a hired bodyguard.
だが 所詮は金で雇われた用心棒
もう戻っては来まい
l doubt that she will return.
お頭は？
How is the commander?
He'll be fine. He's still breathing.
（ユン）大丈夫 息はある
（ジン）お前たちは
お頭を連れて あとから来い
The rest of you, follow me
and carry the commander back.
チャグム皇子を
奪還するという目的は果たした
We've attained our objective of
recapturing Prince Chagum.
l will return with
His Highness without delay.
俺は一刻も早く皇子を連れて帰る
Don't enter the city. You'll attract
too much attention looking like that.
街には入るな
その姿では目立ちすぎる
Well, looks like we're all right
for the time being.
（トーヤ）
とりあえず大丈夫そうだな
My back is stiff as a board...
（トーヤ）
背中がゴワゴワになっちまったよ
なあ サヤ
You know, Saya...
バルサねえさん―
l think Balsa's mixed up
in some ugly business.
かなり ヤバいことに
巻き込まれてると思うんだ
Maybe we should
tell Tanda about this.
（トーヤ）このこと
タンダに知らせるべきじゃないかな
（サヤ）うん 私もそう思う
l think so too.
When Tanda comes to town,
he takes a few days before going home.
タンダは 一度 都に下りたら
何日かは山小屋には戻らない
Which means that he still
ought to be in town somewhere.
…ってことは まだ
都のどこかにいるはずなんだ
うん… でも どうやって捜すの？
Yes, but how do we find him?
なあに このトーヤ様は―
Come on, they don't call me
the best errand runner...
だてに 扇(おうぎ)の下(しも)いちの頼まれ屋って
呼ばれてるわけじゃない
...in Ogi no Shimo for nothing!
We'll just check every inn and
restaurant Tanda might be staying at.
タンダの泊まってそうな
宿から飯屋まで―
片っ端から当たって
調べ出すまでさ
（サヤ）タンダは
薬の注文を確認するのに―
Tanda stops by here every morning
and evening to check his orders.
毎日 朝と晩に立ち寄るの
（トーヤ）へえー
こんなに タンダ宛ての
注文が残ってるってことは…
lf there's still this many orders for
Tanda's medicinal herbs, that means...
...that Tanda hasn't made
his evening pickup yet!
（サヤ）夜の回収は まだなのよ
だから ここで待っていれば…
So if we wait here...
...Tanda is sure to come!
タンダは必ず来る
Oh, l see!
そうか これなら
入れ違いになる心配もないし―
lf we do it this way, there's
no risk of missing him...
...and we won't have to
run all over town either!
街じゅう走らなくて済むな
やっぱり サヤは頭がいいや
l always said that you've got a
good head on your shoulders, Saya!
チャグム皇子に 水妖(すいよう)などという
得体(えたい)の知れぬものが取りつくとは
lt's hard to believe that Prince
Chagum has been possessed by...
...some mysterious water demon.
本当に 帝(みかど)の剣でなければ
成敗できんのだろうか
Can it really only be slain
by His Majesty's own sword?
（チャグム）叱られたのか？
Were you punished for something?
Your Highness!
（侍女１）皇子！
（侍女２）チャグム皇子！
Your Highness!
Prince Chagum!
そうじゃ これを
Oh, l know! Have this.
Your Highness, you mustn't!
（侍女１）皇子 いけません
（チャグム）よいのじゃ
Your Highness, you mustn't!
lt's all right.
うん？ どうした？
甘いものは嫌いか？
What's the matter?
Do you not like sweets?
You needn't be shy.
l was given two.
遠慮するでない 余は２つもらった
Your Highness...
（侍女１）皇子…
l shall leave it here.
ここに置いておくぞ
Thank you for your
kindness, Your Highness!
（ジン）ありがとうございます！
皇子の温かき お心遣い
このジン 生涯忘れません！
l, Jin, shall never forget it
as long as l live!
（ジン）このまま
チャグム皇子を連れて帰れば―
lf l do nothing and bring
Prince Chagum back...
帝 ご自身の手で
皇子を殺さねばならない
...His Majesty will be forced to
slay his son by his own hand.
Such a terrible thing
ought not be allowed.
そのような ひどいことは
断じて許されるべきではない
もし ここで
俺が己の手を汚せば―
lf l were to do it myself
and sully my own hands here...
少なくとも チャグム皇子は
ご自分の父君に殺されずとも済む
...Prince Chagum would at least be
spared death at his father's hand.
それで 俺は
確実に死罪になるであろうが―
l will most certainly be
sentenced to death for the deed.
To lose my life for you would be
my long-cherished ambition!
この身一つ消えたとて
むしろ本望！
チャグム皇子 このご無礼
どうか お許しください！
Prince Chagum, please forgive
the outrage l am about to commit.
But know that everything l do
is for the greater good of Shin-Yogo!
これも皆
新ヨゴ皇国のためにございます
このジンめも すぐに参ります！
Your faithful servant Jin
will join you immediately!
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
タンダのヤツ 何してんだろ？
What on earth is keeping Tanda?
サヤ 俺ちょっと
その辺 見てくるよ
Saya, l'm gonna go
look around over there.
Just sitting around waiting
isn't getting us anywhere!
ここに座ってても
らちがあかねえや
あっ 私は？
What about me?
（トーヤ）サヤは ここにいてくれ
入れ違いになるといけないから
l want you to stay here, Saya.
We can't afford to miss him.
（チャグム）あっ バルサ…
Balsa?
バルサ もう大丈夫じゃ
Balsa, it is all right.
l am able to walk on my own.
余は自分で歩ける
あっ バルサ！ 大丈夫か？
Balsa? Are you all right?
lt's a sad day when a bodyguard
has her charge worrying over her.
用心棒が 守る相手に
心配されてりゃ世話ないね
ひとまず あんただけでも
助かる方法を考えないと
First, l have to think of a way
to keep you safe on your own.
Keep me safe alone?
What do you mean by that?
余だけ助かる？
それは どういうことじゃ！
私も助かるために まずは
あんたが助からなきゃいけないんだ
To save myself,
l have to save you first.
You shouldn't have to
worry needlessly.
余計な心配をするんじゃないよ
いいかい？ よくお聞き
Pay close attention.
lf you continue straight down this path...
この道をまっすぐ行くと―
大きな熊の背中のような形をした
岩が連なってる
...you will see a line of rocks
in the shape of a giant bear's back.
その後ろには
獣道が通っていて―
An animal trail is behind it. Follow it,
and you will come to a meadow.
それをたどっていくと草地に出る
A man named Tanda lives there.
そこに タンダって男が
住んでいるから―
事情を話して
助けてもらうように頼むんだ
Explain the situation to him
and ask him for help.
チャグム
Chagum, when you reach the rock,
climb up and walk along the top.
岩に着いたら まず よじ登って
その上を歩くんだ
You'll see the forest
below you along the way.
途中 森が下に見えるから―
怖いだろうけど 我慢するんだよ
You might be afraid, but bear with it.
The moss will be slippery,
so be careful and walk slowly.
（バルサ）こけが滑るから―
そいつも注意しながら
ゆっくりとね
Near the end of the bear's back,
climb down to the meadow.
熊の背中が終わりに近づいたら
岩を下りて草地に向かいな
lt will look empty at first, but as
you get closer, you will see a hut.
一見 何もないように見えるけど
行けば 必ず小屋があるからね
lf everything's clear...
分かったら…
さっさと… お行き
...then hurry and be on your way.
Balsa? Balsa!
バルサ！ バルサ！
Don't climb off the bear's back
before you reach the end...
熊の背中を
途中で降りるんじゃないよ
A rock like a bear's back...
熊の背中の岩… 熊の背中の岩…
これか
This must be it!
Seriously?
（トーヤ）ホントかい？
その人 湯治場へ行ったんだね？
You're sure he went
to the health springs?
Thanks!
ありがとう！
l better hurry!
急がなきゃ！
向こう側は獣道になっていると
言っておったが…
She said that an
animal trail lies beyond.
This is impossible...
ダメじゃ
やっぱり下から行こう
l think l'll go from down here after all.
オ… オオカミがいる
There are wolves!
lf l lose any more blood,
l'll be in trouble...
これ以上 血を失うと危ないね
このままじゃ
日が昇る前に確実に死ぬ
At this rate, l'll be dead before sunrise.
No question about it.
８人の魂を救ってみせると
豪語して出てきたのに―
When l left, l boasted that l would
save the souls of eight people...
久しぶりに戻ってきてみれば
このザマだ
And now that l have
finally returned, look at me...
（ジグロ）お前が ここに来るのは
分かっていた
l knew that l would find you here.
Hey! Saya! Saya!
（トーヤ）おい サヤ！
サヤ！ 見つけたよ！
l found him!
The old man at the inn said that
Tanda's at the health springs!
宿屋のおやじが
“タンダは湯治場にいる”って
小屋など ないではないか
There is no hut here!
誰か助けて！ 誰か！
Someone! Help me! Somebody!
Are you all right?
（タンダ）大丈夫か？ 君
What in the world
are you doing out here?
いったい
こんな所で何やってるんだ？
A-Are you Tanda?
そ… そちがタンダか？
That's right.
（タンダ）そうだよ
君 運がいいな
You're lucky.
l was in town until recently...
さっきまで都にいたんだけど―
...but l had so many orders today
that l ran out of medicinal herbs.
今日は 注文が多くて
売り物の葉を切らしてね
ちょうど戻ってきたところなんだ
l only returned just now.
書き置きを見てきたのか
Did you come here after
seeing the note l left?
ここまで来るのは 大変だったろうに
lt must have been difficult
to come all this way.
とりあえず中に入って―
For now, come inside and dry yourself.
We can talk afterwards.
体を乾かしなさい 話は それからだ
どうした？
What's the matter?
バルサが…
lt's Balsa!
That's...
あれは…
（タンダ）バルサ！
Balsa!
バルサ！
バルサ！ バルサ！
Balsa, are you all right? Hey! Balsa!
バルサ 大丈夫か？
おい バルサ！ バルサ！
Balsa!
Hey! Balsa!
おい！ バルサ！
As l sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like l was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before l knew it.
lt was none other than you
who was there for me.
l keep wishing, "l want to be strong."
l stumble and hurt myself again.
But because l have you to believe in,
l can get back to my feet.
l simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you."
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
l call out to my precious loved one.
ls my voice reaching you?
ln this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
l'm certain l sensed the presence
of the one that l hold dear.
～♪
Next Time
A wounded woman
and a man who heals.
A reunion of those bound by fate
sets the wheel of fortune in motion.
Next time, "Torogai's Letter."
Episode 4
Torogai's Letter
That which a magic weaver opens...
...is a gateway to another world.